Just wanted to start off by uh thanking
Dave and Nicole Ter for their trust and
support uh throughout the whole process.
Um they're committed to winning, easy to
work with, and uh just can't thank them
enough just for the support through the
whole free agent process. Um, also want
to thank the pro department, um,
analytics, Brandt Tillis and his crew,
um, player player engagement, football
ops, uh, everybody was awesome. The the
coach, Coach Canales and his staff, they
were very helpful through the whole
process. Uh, so I can't thank everybody
enough just for everything they've done,
all the hard hard work that they put in.
Um, we got a great team here. Um, we
were able to retain a lot of our own.
Um, go outside the building and sign
some free agents that were really
excited about. Uh, I felt like, you
know, having that depth and, you know,
and frontline players um, that we added
in free agency. I think it really gives
us a lot of flexibility headed into the
draft to draft the best available
player.
Um, so again, I'm just excited about the
direction that we're headed, that the
franchise is headed. Um, and we're on to
the draft now. And, you know, that's
another exciting time where we can add
really quality players to our roster.
And, uh, we're ready to go. So, with
that, I'll open it up to any questions.
>> We'll kick things off with Darren Gant,
followed by Mike Kay.
Go ahead. Dan, with your context as a
former linebacker, how does that kind of
color the way you look at a Jaylen
Phillips, the way you look at a Devin
Lloyd, and the kind of impact they can
make?
>> Yeah, you know, um I think Devin and
Jaylen are two guys that we obviously
held in high regard during free agency.
Uh when you look at both those guys
physically, how how big they are, um how
long they are, um the effort that they
play with, the way they prepare,
um they were definitely guys that we had
our eyes on during free agency, uh me
being a former player and and watching
them on tape, they have everything that
you want in terms of the motor, the
effort, the instincts, the range that
they play with. Uh, so they they were
really good ads for us and and guys that
we're really excited about and they're
really going to help our defense moving
forward.
>> Do you ever catch yourself thinking
either one of them really? Okay. He kind
of reminds me of fill in the blank,
somebody you were with or somebody
you've seen along the way?
>> Uh, not not really. Uh, I don't really
have anybody that I would compare them
to. I just know they're two guys that I
obviously scouted coming out of college
that I held in high regard then and to
be able to get them in free agency.
They're just going to add so much to our
defense along with the guys that we
already have. Uh we're just really
excited about adding them and adding the
type of players and leaders that they
are in the locker room, the way they
prepare, the way they just approach
their day-to-day. They're everything
that we wanted.
Hey Dan. Um,
>> what's up Mike?
>> Hey, how's it going? You were pretty
overt in your desire to to add a more
mobile and younger quarterback. You did
that with Kenny Picket.
There obviously was an agreement on a
trade with Philadelphia with Andy
Dalton. I know that hasn't been
completed yet or at least announced
officially.
>> Yeah. You had said that Andy didn't mind
competing and you had said that you guys
were keeping in touch with him. Why
trade him now? And what is the outlook
for the position heading into the draft?
>> Yeah, I think uh we feel good about our
quarterback room. Um you know, going
going back to Andy, he Andy's a guy that
we hold in high regard here. Uh he
really helped Bryce, you know, come
along as a rookie and you know, into his
third year. Um, so Andy just he bought a
lot to our franchise. I can't thank him
enough for what he bought. Um, and just
the the type of man he is as well. So I
definitely wish him the best. Um, adding
Kenny Picket, I feel like, you know,
adding a mobile quarterback, I think in
this league, you
mobility
I think is big in this league. So, I
think adding a guy like Kenny Picket
that can move outside the pocket if he
needs to, create with his legs if he
needs to, um, I think those are all
things that were really intriguing to
us. And heading into the the draft, um,
I think, you know, there's there's going
to be options there. Whether they're the
best player at the time, uh, is yet to
be seen, but, you know, if we have the
opportunity to add another young guy to
the mix, uh, we'll do that.
And then you brought in Rasheed Walker
and AJ Dylan on on one-year deals, Luke
Forner as well. But with the Walker and
Dylan signings, obviously you have two
players coming off injury there. What is
your outlook on Icky a couple of months
removed from surgery as well as Jonathan
Brooks as he heads into what is an
important season for you guys?
>> Yeah, those uh you know, Brooks and uh
Icky, they're they're making progress.
They're with our trainers every day.
They're looking good. Uh they're working
their butts off. I don't have a timeline
on that to update update you with. Um
but both those guys, they're headed in a
good direction. Um you know, I think
those two guys are are guys that, you
know, we're looking to to add to our
team that they're going to hopefully be
healthy at some point. And um you know,
we'll just go from there.
We'll go with Joe Pson followed by David
Newton.
>> Hey Dan, good afternoon.
>> Hey, what's up Joe?
>> Uh, not too much. Um, when you say you
don't have a timeline for Icky, is that
do you mean that's there's one that you
don't want to share publicly? I'm
guessing you have one internally that's
going to shape how you address the
draft. And I wonder if you, you know,
could address that with us, how your
view and the the franchise's view of
Icky's recovery could impact the ability
or or potential that you you take a uh
tackle.
>> Yeah, I think uh timelinewise with Icky,
um I I don't have any updates. You know,
everybody recovers differently from
injuries. He's making really good
progress. He looks really good. Um but
in terms of timeline, we we don't know
that. So obviously
um signing Rasheed Walker, you know, we
always have to have a backup plan. We
always got to be prepared. There's
inevitably going to be injuries in this
league and and that's for every
position. So, um, in terms of adding
Rasheed Walker, like, you know, we're
excited about him and and what he's
going to be able to bring and, you know,
I think, uh, that definitely gives time
to, you know, recover and, you know,
when we get him back, we'll be excited
to have him back, but timeline wise, I
don't know that. And on on Walker,
bringing him on just the one-year deal,
does that leave open the possibility to
that give you that flexibility that you
mentioned in the draft at that position
in particular?
>> Um, I think it gives us the flexibility
to really draft the best available
players. Um, so, you know, if a tackle
is the best available player, you know,
at that point, then so be it. But, um, I
think it definitely gives us that
flexibility heading into the draft that
we can, you know, be aggressive and and
add really good players to our team.
>> And then lastly on Rasheed, he had a a
gun charge in January. How much vetting
did you guys do and were you satisfied
with what you found out?
>> Um, you know, that's a a pending legal
matter right now, so I really can't
comment on that, but we did our
research.
>> Thank you. Yep.
David.
>> Hey Dan, good to see you. Sorry I was
having David.
I appreciate your time here. Um,
with the this whole situation that Joe
was asking about with Rasheed and Icky,
um, how much what happened with Yash
catch you off guard? Um, first off, you
know, Yash obviously is a he's a really
good person, uh, a player that we did
want to bring back. Um, me being in his
shoes, uh, as as a former player, um, I
really understand what he was going
through. He was trying to decide if he
wanted to play or not. Uh, caught us a
little off guard, but, you know, again,
I've been there. I understand what he's
thinking. I have a lot of respect for
him and his decision. And you know, just
like every position in this league, you
have to have backup plans. And you know,
I think we did a good job pivoting and
and adding to that position.
>> And you were again, you were pretty
emphatic what you wanted to improve. And
it seems like you just got everybody you
were looking for. I mean, was there was
there a miss or something that you
didn't get that you kind of on your wish
list that you kind of hope to have right
now? Yeah, I mean, we felt we feel
really good about what we did and what
we accomplished in free agency. I think
we, you know, definitely hit on who we
wanted to hit on and and we're really
happy with that. And again, it gives us
a lot of flexibility heading into the
draft to be able to do what, you know,
we want to do and draft the best
available players. Mhm. And and have you
uh gotten like as far as your draft
list, are you planning to bring in 30
now or kind of where you guys are with
your uh list of college guys you're
looking at?
>> Yeah. Yeah, we'll bring in guys on on
the 30 visit and you know, we're going
to definitely be strategic in who we
bring in and why we bring them in. And
uh we definitely have a plan and process
in place of of who we do want to bring
in. And um look forward to seeing those
guys and talking to them. Okay. And I
appreciate it. And one more question on
Jaylen. Um,
his story is really interesting. How how
concerned were you with the injury
history he had?
>> Obviously, we do our research and we
feel really good about it. Otherwise, we
wouldn't have invested the money that we
did in him. We know the type of worker
he is and and where he is from an injury
standpoint. So, we feel really good
about him moving forward and and what
he's going to bring to our team.
Appreciate it. Thanks a lot.
>> Yep.
>> Alex Zerlo followed by Jeff Hawkins.
>> Hello, Dan. Happy Friday.
>> What's up, Alex?
>> Hey, what's up, man? Um, I you touched
on this earlier, but I wanted to ask I
wanted wondered if you could elaborate.
Why um was Kenny Picket someone that you
wanted to bring in uh to Carolina? Yeah,
you know, I think Coach Canales, I think
Kenny was a guy that coach really wanted
to work with and and was fond of in the
um evaluation process. Um I'll go back
to what I said before, the mobility and
and his ability to create with his legs,
I think, was a big part of that.
um obviously he can throw the ball and
and he has a lot of a lot of upside and
um I think like every player you know he
knows that he can get better at certain
things but we're excited about him
>> and then I also wanted to ask the same
of John Mchky the third wide receiver.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Another guy that we're
excited to have obviously Bryce is
familiar with him. they played together
in college and I know Bryce is really
fond of him, you know, not only as a
player but as a person. Um, I just think
it's another, you know, another piece
that we can add to our receiver room
that adds depth and competition in that
room. And, you know, I think that's what
we're trying to do at every spot is just
add as much depth and competition as we
can.
>> Great. Thanks.
>> Yep.
Hey, good afternoon. How you doing?
>> Good. How you doing?
>> Good. Um, when you and coach took over,
uh, the franchise ranked near the bottom
in the NFL PA player polls, but now
after signing three, you know, immediate
starters in free agency and filling key
backup positions before the draft, how
how much pride are you taking in
developing a locker room culture that is
attracting top talent to Charlotte
again?
Yeah, you know, I think uh coach has
done a really good job in terms of the
culture and you know, you got to give a
lot of credit to the players in our
locker room as well. Uh we have really
great guys in our locker room. They're
not only great players, but they're
great people and and that's what we're
trying to bring in here. We're trying to
bring in not only quality football
players but quality people and people
that impact the community and um you
know I think that that's a big part of
the culture around here is you know that
family atmosphere that we're trying to
attract players from the outside they
know that when they come into this
building that they have full support
from ownership myself coach Canales. Um,
so we're just trying to build that
family atmosphere around here to where
hey, you're you're we're not valuing you
just solely based on what you do on the
field, but we also care about you off
the field as well. So that's the message
that we're trying to send around here.
>> Hey, thanks.
>> We'll go with Cass followed by Daryl
Hortwitz.
>> Hey Dan, how's it going?
>> Good. How you doing?
>> Good. Sorry, my camera's not working.
Just imagine I'm there. You're good.
>> Um, special teams a lot of times can be
kind of piece together, but y'all
brought back not only Sam, but like kind
of that core with Enkum and Isaiah
Simmons and a Caleb Evans. Like, why was
it so important to keep that group
together?
>> Yeah, you know, I think they're they're
guys that aren't only good on special
teams, they can add value on the
defensive side and add depth on the
defensive side as well. And again,
they're guys culture-wise that that we
hold in high regard around here as well,
not only being just great players, but
just great people. Um, so it was
important for us to get them back and,
you know, just keep our depth, keep our
numbers at the position strong, and you
know, they're guys that are really going
to help us out moving forward.
>> And then one other quick thing, just
wanted to follow up on Mitchi. just due
to injuries and chemotherapy, you know,
he hasn't had a ton of production since
being in the league. Did you go back and
and watch that tape with Bryce at all
from Alabama or or lean on Bryce just
kind of for evaluation? What all went
into that process?
>> Yeah. Yeah, I definitely talked to Bryce
about him. Obviously, the type of person
he is and and the player. Um, so yeah, I
did my homework there talking to Bryce,
but you know, I think he's a he's still
young and a guy that um he's had some
production in this league. Hasn't been
as consistent as he's wanted to be, but
I think there's definitely a lot of
upside there. And uh we'll see where it
goes. You know, he's going to have a
chance to compete like the rest of the
guys, and I'm looking forward to seeing
that.
>> Awesome. Thank you.
>> Yep.
Hey Dan, uh you aggressively approached
free agency getting the defense, you
know, obviously a place of need. Let me
ask you when you were talking about like
Jaylen Phillips and the money you gave
him under the circumstances of his
output so far, I mean, he had a lot of
hurries, but he hasn't had a lot of
sacks in his career. So, when you're
looking at him, how are you projecting
what you're seeing now or what he's
doing versus getting the sacks? And how
important is it for those hurries to
translate into sacks for this free agent
pickup to be worth what you're looking
for?
>> Yeah, I don't I don't think uh it's all
about sacks, you know. I think uh
Jaylen's a disruptive guy. Um and that
can be just as impactful. Um maybe it
doesn't look sexy, you know, on the box
score at the end of the game in terms of
having sacks on there, but he's
disruptive play in and play out. He's
not only a good pass rusher, but he's
also really good against the run. Um and
he's a guy that can make an impact just
chasing the ball and and running ball
carriers down. So, he brings a lot more
than just pass rush to the to the
defense. He brings a guy with a high
motor. uh his efforts outstanding and
he's physical at the point of attack. He
can do a lot of things other than rush
the passer. So looking forward to him
just keep improving and and getting
better and I know he's committed to that
and uh we're definitely excited about
him.
>> One last question. Uh how did last
season in the free agency affect your
aggressiveness going into this off
season?
Um, I wouldn't say that it really
impacted it. I mean, we try to be
aggressive in every aspect. Um, not just
free agency, but just on like a
day-to-day standpoint. You know, if a
guy that we like hits the waiver wire,
then we'll be aggressive to claim them
or we're going to be aggressive in every
avenue to make this team better, whether
through free agency or just the
day-to-day waiver wire, uh, trades, etc.
So, uh, we just have that aggressive
mindset.
>> Thank you, Dan.
>> Yep.
>> We have time for a couple more. We'll go
with Mike K, followed by Joe Person.
Dan, um, you had mentioned earlier that
you guys hit the positions you wanted to
hit, but during your planning, I mean,
when you were formulating your plan, was
there a position in free agency that you
thought was kind of difficult to attack
during the free agency period and that
you would have to rely on maybe
resignings or or the draft as you kind
of looked at the the landscape so that
you could focus in on inside and outside
linebacker?
Um, I don't think we really looked at it
like that. We We had our plan in place,
uh, which was the sign who we thought
was the best players. Um, fortunately,
we got that done and and feel really
good about getting that done and what
they're going to bring to our team. Um,
so yeah, I I feel good about, you know,
filling the outside linebacker, filling
inside linebacker, and again, giving us
flexibility in the draft move moving
forward.
Do you believe will Jatavian Sanders be
I know he just had ankle surgery. Will
he be ready in time for OTAAS and the
offseason program?
>> Yeah, he's making a lot of progress. Um
I think he should be ready. Um that I
see him in there every day working with
the trainers and definitely have gotten
good reports on him. He's looking great
physically. Uh he's working his butt off
so I I suspect that he'll be ready.
>> Thank you.
Dan, after you guys had that initial
wave on the first day, it became a
series of of one-year deals, many of
them at at uh numbers that were lower
than projected. How important was it to,
you know, kind of do that and and kind
of get some, if you will, some value
signings achieved after you had made the
commitment to Jaylen and Devon? Yeah, I
think it's really important um just to
fill out your roster and and add that
depth and that competition that I talked
about before. Um so, yeah, one-year
deals, guys that, you know, we think can
help our team immediately. Uh guys that
are going to compete and just add depth
and competition to, you know, different
position groups.
>> And then you had said a minute ago or a
couple minutes ago that you're on to the
draft. is if might you still do a few or
a couple things late in free agency or
you think you're done?
>> Uh there might be a few moves here and
there. Um you know guys that you know we
think we might be able to get. Um but
yeah, we're we're always going to be
looking. We're always going to be
aggressive. There's always going to be
guys out there that you you know that
aren't signed that you know you think
should be signed that it may be an
opportunity for us to get better. And
you know, if we feel like they'll make
us better, then you know, we'll
definitely explore it.
>> Thanks.
>> Yep.
>> Any more questions for Dan?
>> Yeah, I got one. This is David again.
Dan, were there any anxious moments on
that first day or or kind of tell me
what they were and what was the emotion
because you guys got Jaylen pretty
quick. Did you have pretty good
confidence going in that you were going
to get him that quickly? No, I mean
that's the part about free agency that
you hate. You just you just never know.
So, obviously there's always going to be
anxious moments. There's, you know,
there's 31 other teams that you're
competing against and, you know, you
don't know what's true. You don't you
don't know what to believe. So, yeah,
there's definitely anxious moments. Um,
but we felt good about, you know, what
we're building here and attracting
players here. We felt like players
wanted to be here. um as opposed to when
I first took over, you know, was maybe a
little harder. So, uh you definitely
feel that shift and you know, guys
really wanting to be here and, you know,
be a part of of what we're building
here.
>> Can you expand on that? What were they
telling you to make you feel they wanted
to be there versus what you felt back a
few years ago? Yeah, I think just, you
know, once you get the deals done and,
you know, you talk to the guys, you
know, you could just feel their
excitement about being here and, um,
they all felt like our team was an upand
cominging team that was trending in the
right direction. They all heard really
good things about Coach Canales, the
staff, and just the the culture around
here. So, uh, that definitely made me
believe that, you know, things are are
trending upwards here.
Hey,
hey,